<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>on Development Cheat Sheets</title><link>http://example.org/index.html</link><description>Recent content in on Development Cheat Sheets</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 10:28:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Posts</title><link>http://example.org/posts/index.html</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 10:28:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/index.html</guid><description>Posts Building images with Kaniko in JenkinsAn overview of how I set up Jenkins to be able to build (docker) images with kaniko inside my Kubernetes cluster.
Dell Inspiron 7537 - Preventing Linux shutdown when closing the lidThis is a little post about how to prevent a Dell Inspiron laptop from shutting down or going into standby when you close the lid on the laptop.
Hack for SQLite use on KubernetesThis page captures a technique I developed to work around the issues you can encounter when using Persistent Volumes (PVs) that contain SQLite databases used by containers in Kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Concepts</title><link>http://example.org/concepts/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/concepts/index.html</guid><description/></item><item><title>Hardware</title><link>http://example.org/hardware/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/hardware/index.html</guid><description>This section contains pages and links to some of the hardware that I have come across.
Pages Broadlink (Black Bean) DevicesThe Broadlink (RM Mini) black bean is a small universal Infra Red (IR) remote control which connects to and receives commands over WiFi.
Raspberry PiThe Raspberry Pi is a series of small single-board computers (SBCs) developed in the United Kingdom by the Raspberry Pi Foundation in association with Broadcom.</description></item><item><title>Interesting...</title><link>http://example.org/to_research/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/to_research/index.html</guid><description>&lt;p>This page captures some the interesting tech that I have heard about, but have not had a chance to investigate/use.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Operating Systems</title><link>http://example.org/operating-systems/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/operating-systems/index.html</guid><description>This page contains information about the operating systems that I have come across throughout my career (read journey) as a software developer.
Pages AlpineAlpine Linux is a Linux distribution designed to be small, simple, and secure.
DebianThe Linux Debian operating system is used as the base for many other linux operating systems such as Ubuntu and the Raspberry Pi OS (formerly Raspbian).
LinuxLinux is a family of open-source Unix-like operating systems based on the Linux kernel, an operating system kernel first released on September 17, 1991, by Linus Torvalds.</description></item><item><title>Programming Languages</title><link>http://example.org/languages/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/languages/index.html</guid><description>Pages Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) is a style sheet language used for describing the presentation of a document written in a markup language such as HTML or XML (including XML dialects such as SVG, MathML or XHTML).
Command Prompt (cmd.exe)cmd.exe is the default command-line interpreter for OS/2, eComStation, Windows, Windows CE, and the ReactOS operating systems.
GoGo is a statically typed, compiled high-level programming language designed at Google.</description></item><item><title>Tools</title><link>http://example.org/tools/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/tools/index.html</guid><description>This page contains links to the tools that I have discovered, and documented, as a part of my development journey.
Pages AnsibleAnsible provides open-source automation that reduces complexity and runs everywhere.
Apache HTTP server (httpd)The Apache HTTP Server is a free and open-source cross-platform web server software, released under the terms of Apache License 2.0.
AWS Command Line Interface (CLI)The AWS Command Line Interface (CLI) is a unified tool to manage AWS services.</description></item></channel></rss>